Anuj Bhatnagar 🔾 Featured

Blueprism Certified, RPA Developer seeking roles in Software
Development,SDLC,Project Management,Requirement Analysis,Solution
Design,Process Automation,Change Management,Problem Management,Report
Generation, RPA, Blueprism,.NET,JIRA, Confluence



Current Designation: Senior Developer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 7 Month(s)

Current Company: Nityo Infotech Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Delhi Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Electrical]

Pref. Location: Mumbai, Pune, Delhi / NCR

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: RPA Developer, Software Developer, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Process Automation, Release Management, Problem Management, Report Generation, Service Management, HTML, JIRA, blueprism, blue prism, ROBOTIC

PROCESS AUTOMATION, RPA, Confluence

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

Blue Prism certified developer -AD01.

Analyzing the process and design he Robotic Automation Solution as per the Blue Prism best practices.

Having hands on experience on different aspects of Blue Prism like control room, object studio, process studio, system manager, release manager.

Experienced in RPA Life Cycle Documentation like, IPA, PDD, FRQ, SDD, etc.

Experienced into different application spying mode like Win32, Access, Region, HTML and UI Automation and SAP mode. Experienced in Exception Handling and Queue Management Concepts.

Good Exposure in working with complex Excel?s, OLEDB, PDF Files, CSV Files, SQL Database and E-mail Automation. Hands on experience in working with Windows, Web, Excel, Mainframe and SAP automations.

Demonstrated various POC?s for various BP automation projects.

Excellent requirement analysis and development skills with complete knowledge of SDLC starting from requirement gathering till post-production support.

Work Experience

Nityo Infotech as Senior Developer Sep 2020 to Till Date

SENIOR RPA Developer for Client -ASWATSON - Hong Kong

Global Cloud Xchange as RPA Developer-Blueprism

May 2015 to Sep 2020

Blue Prism certified developer -AD01.

Analyzing the process and design he Robotic Automation Solution as per the Blue Prism best practices.

Having hands on experience on different aspects of Blue Prism like control room, object studio, process studio, system manager, release manager.

Experienced in RPA Life Cycle Documentation like, IPA, PDD, FRQ, SDD, etc.

Experienced into different application spying mode like Win32, Access, Region, HTML and UI Automation and SAP mode.

Experienced in Exception Handling and Queue Management Concepts.

Good Exposure in working with complex Excel?s, OLEDB, PDF Files, CSV Files, SQL Database and E-mail Automation.

Hands on experience in working with Windows, Web, Excel, Mainframe and SAP automations.

Demonstrated various POC?s for various BP automation projects.

Excellent requirement analysis and development skills with complete knowledge of SDLC starting from requirement gathering till postproduction support.

- ? Insightful knowledge on ITIL (Incident, Change, Problem Management)
- ? Ability to work as a team member or as an individual and confident in serving the best result.
- ? Strong communication and client interaction skills.
- ? Ability to quickly grasp any new technologies and concepts.
- ? Experience on Managing day-day operations of RPA executions.
- ? Created Functional Requirements Documents (FRDs) for an RPA project, based on Business Process Design discussions with business stakeholders.
- ? Worked on Agile Scrum environment.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electrical) from Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya (RGPV), Bhopal in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

AD01- Blueprism

ITIL V3

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	d Experience	
C#				
JavaScript, HTML				
SQL				
Blue Prism	6.0	2020	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Windows (7, Server 2008, Server 2012)				
HP QUALITY Center				
SNOW, JIRA, Remedy.				

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Finance automations

Client: Reliance Capital

Nature of Employment: Full Time
Project Location: Mumbai
Role: Sr. Programmer

Duration: Jun 2017 - Till Date
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite
Team Size: 4

Skill Used: Blueprism

Role Description: * Process and Objects Development and their integration.

* BE Report generation at the end of the process, which helps in knowing the cases which are complete and cases which are to be handled manually.

Project Details: Brief description of the client:

Reliance Capital is amongst Indias leading and most valuable financial services companies in the private sector. Reliance

1/22/2021 https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=b56db035110ff7c5fb65f9c296eda4045e0b0d001f1708420445105c5a5a...

Capital has interests in asset management and mutual funds; life and general insurance; commercial finance; equities and commodities broking and many more in financial services.

Project Exposure: I have engaged in development and well as providing production support to the client.

Team size: 4

Book Optimization: This process involves generation of documents in web application named as seismic and validation of the same.

Concept Used: Various aspects of BP such as Queue Management, MS Excel VBO, MS outlook VBO, Dynamic attributes. This process has reduced the AHT (Average Handling Time) of thus providing better customer experience and accuracy.

Environment: Blue Prism V6.X, MS Excel .NET, VBA, SQL Server, Visual Studio, MS Office, Windows 10.

Finance Process Automation: The aim of this implementation is to replace the daily

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time